

Artur Teixeira +351 911 076 566 info@artur-teixeira.tech

https://artur-teixeira.tech https://www.linkedin.com/in/arturjnt/ https://twitter.com/arturint

Summary

Working since 2014 on Software, Artur has been through every job on the field, from a ticket-grabbing developer, through full-stack, infrastructure, database management, continuous delivery, frontend and backend engineering, and even information security.

Working directly with business owners and clients is something Artur has years of experience in, therefore he understands the value of translating a vision into an actionable roadmap and its features.

Skills

- Web
- o Node | Vue | React | HTML | CSS | Sass | tailwindcss
- No-code: Webflow | Squarespace | Wordpress
- DBs
- NoSQL | SQL | Firebase | GraphQL
- Mobile
- Flutter | Dart
- Infrastructure
- o AWS | Azure | OVH (VPS) | Firebase | Grafana
- CI/CE
- Jenkins | CircleCI | Linux CLI
- Management Tools
- o Git | JIRA | Trello | Figma | ProductBoard | Sketch
- IT Security
- o GDPR (DPIAs) | Pen-Tests | Cookie Law

Languages

- Native Portuguese
- Fluent English
- Limited proficiency in Spanish

Education

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto (ISEP) BSc Informatics Engineering (2011-2014)

Introduction to several languages, platforms, frameworks, engineering principles and patterns.

Experience

<u>Self-Employed - https://artur-teixeira.tech/</u> Freelance Software Engineer (July 2021 - Now)

I will discuss, organize and develop apps and websites for anyone.

Developed websites in React.JS (with and without Gatsby); GraphQL and SQL; automated deploy to Netlify and built several apps from the ground up with Flutter and Firebase. Implemented infrastructure using Azure and worked a lot with AWS and Grafana.

Built websites using "builders" like Squarespace and Wordpress, while developing a custom theme using PHP. I've also done some Security Engineering for an SMB and consulted regarding architecture analysis and estimation for a multinational organization.

skeeled

Head of R&D (March 2017 - June 2021)

Management of Software Engineering, Quality Assurance, UI/UX Design and Data Science teams (15 ppl.), for the development of an online recruitment platform.

skeeled

Lead Software Engineer (November 2015 - February 2017)

Working in the architecture, development and deployment of an online recruitment platform.

Tech:

- Frontend: AngularJS, Vue.js, HTML5 & Sass
- Grunt, NPM, Bower, Bootstrap
- NodeJS & Express
- MongoDB
- git, JIRA & Pivotal Tracker

DevOps:

- (AWS) S3, EC2 & Code Deploy
- CodeShip, Rollbar, PM2 Keymetrics

TOP Docs

Full Stack Dev (April 2015 - October 2015)

Working in the (Full Stack) development of TopDocs platform for iOS & Web.

Tech:

- Android
- NodeJS, AngularJS & ExpressJS + SASS
- PHP & ShellScript
- · Extensive use of GIT

DevOps:

- Azure Web Apps & Virtual Machines
- SQL (MySQL) and NoSQL (MongoDB)
- Automation tool for iOS tests

Jumia Porto Tech Center (Rocket Internet)

PHP Dev (September 2014 - April 2015)

Development of an e-commerce app.

Tech:

- PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL & Solr
- Yii and Zend frameworks (PHP)
- Git